Inventory of the Carter Family Papers 1667-1862
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- People Files, 1667-1862. (Folder 1-102)
  - Carter, (Robert W.) 1792-1861; 1803-1862, n.d. (Folder 20-101)
    - Letters, 1803-1861. (Folder 20-50)
      - Letters (L-Z), n.d. (Folder 50)
        - L.L. Woollard to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, [near] Warsaw P.O., Richmond County, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 50)
        - [?], at Sabine Hall, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Newport, Rhode Island, n.d., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 50)
        - [?] to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, n.d., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 50)
        - n.d., 1 item. (Folder 50)
    - Accounts, 1821-1861. (Folder 51-84)
      - Cash Accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1821-1861., 103 items, including 11 cash books. (Folder 51-53)
      - Bank Acccounts of Robert W. Carter, 1825-1861, n.d. (Folder 54-59)
        - Bank accounts with the Bank of Commerce, Fredericksburg, Virginia, 1854-1862., 191 items. (Folder 54)
          - Letters, 1854-1859., 14 items. (Folder 54)
          - Checks, 1854-1861., 176 items. (Folder 54)
          - Bank Book, 1854-1862., 1 item. (Folder 54)
        - Bank accounts with the Bank of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia, 1839-1861., 46 items. (Folder 55)
          - Letters, 1839-1861., 30 items. (Folder 55)
          - Checks, 1843-1844., 8 items. (Folder 55)
          - Statements, 1843-1861., 8 items. (Folder 55)
        - Bank accounts with the Bank of Virginia, Fredericksburg, Virginia, 1825-1858., 478 items. (Folder 56-57)
          - Letters, 1829-1858., 78 items. (Folder 56-57)
          - Checks, 1825-1854., 395 items. (Folder 56-57)
          - Statements, 1825-1854., 3 items. (Folder 56-57)
          - Bank Books, 1837-1854., 2 items. (Folder 56-57)
        - Bank accounts with the Exchange Bank of Virginia, at Alexandria, 1825-1851., 8 items. (Folder 58)
          - Letters, 1825-1851., 3 items. (Folder 58)
          - Checks, 1848-1849., 5 items. (Folder 58)
        - Bank accounts with the F. Slaughter & Co., Banking and Exchange Office, Fredericksburg, Virginia, 1857-1862, n.d., 19 items. (Folder 59)
          - Checks, 1857-1861., 17 items. (Folder 59)
          - Bank Books, 1857-1862., 1 item. (Folder 59)
          - Memorandum, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 59)
      - Accounts for books, periodicals, and music of Robert W. Carter, 1822-1861., 105 items. (Folder 60)
      - Church accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1825-1859., 23 items. (Folder 61)
      - Clothing accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1820-1861., 207 items. (Folder 62)
      - County and city officials' accounts with Robert W. Carter, 1815-1860., 137 items. (Folder 63)
        Bills and receipts.
        Arranged in alphabetical order by County or City name.
        - Alexandria - Clerk of Alexandria Circuit Court, 1855-1857., 3 items. (Folder 63)
        - Essex County, 1845-1855., 3 items. (Folder 63)
          - Clerk of Essex Circuit Court, 1845., 1 item. (Folder 63)
          - Sheriff of Essex County, 1845-1855., 2 items. (Folder 63)
        - Fredericksburg, 1822-1859., 6 items. (Folder 63)
          - Clerk of Fredericksburg Chancery Court, 1822., 1 item. (Folder 63)
          - Corporation of Fredericksburg (taxes), 1855-1859., 4 items. (Folder 63)
          - Marshal of Fredericksburg Chancery Court, 1827., 1 item. (Folder 63)
        - King George County - Clerk of King George County Court, 1843, 1 item. (Folder 63)
        - Lancaster County, 1830-1843., 2 items. (Folder 63)
          - Clerk of Lancaster County Court, 1843., 1 item. (Folder 63)
          - Clerk of Lancaster Superior Court, 1830., 1 item. (Folder 63)
        - Northumberland County - Clerk of Northumberland County Court, 1837-1840., 2 items. (Folder 63)
        - Richmond County, 1817-1860., 101 items. (Folder 63)
          - Clerk of Richmond County Court, 1825-1848., 14 items. (Folder 63)
          - Commissioner of Revenue, 1817-1855., 10 items. (Folder 63)
          - Commissioner of Superior Court of Chancery for Richmond Circuit, 1847., 1 item. (Folder 63)
          - Coroner of Richmond County, 1823-1834., 4 items. (Folder 63)
          - Overseer of the Poor, 1826-1849., 4 items. (Folder 63)
          - Sheriff of Richmond County, 1815-1860., 66 items. (Folder 63)
            Eight items include levies for the repair of Totuskey Large Bridge, 1841, and Totuskey Little Bridge, 1851.
          - Surveyor of Richmond County, 1835-1854., 4 items. (Folder 63)
        - Spotsylvania, 1851-1860., 7 items. (Folder 63)
          - Clerk of Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery of Spotsylvania County, 1851., 1 item. (Folder 63)
          - Sheriff of Spotsylvania County, 1855-1860., 6 items. (Folder 63)
        - Westmoreland, 1845-1852., 9 items. (Folder 63)
          - Clerk of Westmoreland County Court, 1845-1852., 8 items. (Folder 63)
          - Sheriff of Westmoreland County, 1847., 1 item. (Folder 63)
        - Other Accounts, 1853-1857., 3 items. (Folder 63)
      - Doctors' and druggists' accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1813-1861., 100 items. (Folder 64)
      - Freight, express, drayage, and storage accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1827-1861., 148 items. (Folder 65)
      - Funeral expenses [for Catherine Carter], 28 Aug 1858., 1 item. (Folder 66)
        Memorandum sent by J. S. Wellford to Robert W. Carter.
      - Household accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1822-1861., 238 items. (Folder 67)
      - Insurance accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1843-1861., 20 items. (Folder 68)
      - Investment of Robert W. Carter, 1823-1861., 368 items. (Folder 69-70)
        - Lists of stocks and notes, 1845-1859., 13 items. (Folder 69)
        - Bonds and notes receivable, 1823-1861., 166 items. (Folder 69)
        - Stocks, 1838-1861, 189 items. (Folder 70)
          Arranged by alphabetical order.
          - Bank of Commerce, Fredericksburg, 1856-1857., 5 items. (Folder 70)
          - James Brown, Jr., broker, Richmond, 1852-1853., 5 items. (Folder 70)
          - Exchange Bank of Virginia, Richmond, Alexandria, and Norfolk, 1849-1861., 26 items. (Folder 70)
          - Falmouth Cotton Factory, 1846-1847., 3 items. (Folder 70)
          - Falmouth Manufacturing Co., 1838-1839., 6 items. (Folder 70)
          - Josiah Lee, broker, Baltimore, 1847-1850., 8 items. (Folder 70)
          - James H. Lynch, broker, Richmond, 1841-1850., 15 items. (Folder 70)
          - Manchester Cotton & Wool Manufacturing Co., Richmond, 1850-1861., 15 items. (Folder 70)
            This includes the Report of the Investigating Committee to the stockholders, 1855.
          - New Steam Boat Co., 1851-1854., 3 items. (Folder 70)
          - Old Dominion Steam Boat Co., Fredericksburg, 1853-1857., 8 items. (Folder 70)
          - F. Slaughter & Co., Banking and Exchange Office, Fredericksburg, 1854-1860., 58 items. (Folder 70)
          - White Sulphur Springs Corporation, Greenbrier County, 1852-1861., 27 items. (Folder 70)
          - Other stock accounts, including statements of stocks owned by Robert W. Carter, 1843-1860., 10 items. (Folder 70)
      - Lawyers' accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1834-1856., 7 item. (Folder 71)
      - Militia accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1831-1832., 5 items. (Folder 71)
      - Notes payable of Robert W. Carter, 1820-1854., 46 items. (Folder 71)
      - Plantation accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1813-1861., 1,246 items. (Folder 72-79)
        - Grain accounts and correspondence, 1843-1861., 444 items. (Folder 72-75)
          - Grain accounts and correspondence with Ball & Roy, commission merchants, Baltimore, Maryland, 1853-1855., 32 items. (Folder 72)
          - Grain accounts and correspondence with Ball, Clarke & Co., commission merchants, Baltimore, Maryland, 1855-1856., 66 items. (Folder 72)
          - Grain accounts and correspondence with James McConky & Co., commission merchants, Baltimore, Maryland, 1846-1853., 159 items. (Folder 73)
          - Grain accounts and correspondence with McConky, Parr & Co., commission merchants, Baltimore, Maryland, 1853-1861., 126 items. (Folder 74)
          - Grain accounts and correspondence with William McDonald & Co., Baltimore, Maryland, 1843-1845., 33 items. (Folder 75)
          - Grain accounts and correspondence with George W. Richardson & Co., Baltimore, Maryland, 1845-1846., 28 items. (Folder 75)
        - Grain accounts and correspondence with George W. Richardson & Co., Baltimore, Maryland, 1845-1846., 38 items, including one memorandum book. (Folder 76)
        - Other grain accounts and correspondence, 1820-1861., 89 items. (Folder 76)
        - Lumber, construction and repairs, 1822-1860., 56 items. (Folder 77)
        - Accounts dealing with Negroes, 1813-1861., 123 items. (Folder 77)
          - Accounts and correspondence with Philip M. Tabb & Son, slave dealers, Richmond, Virginia, 1844-1857., 44 items. (Folder 77)
          - Other accounts and correspondence concerning negroes, 1813-1861., 79 items. (Folder 77)
        - Plantation accounts and correspondence of Robert W. Carter with various individuals, 1826-1860., 208 items. (Folder 78)
          Arranged by alphabetical order by last name.
          - A.B. Allen & Co., New York, 1850-1852., 28 items. (Folder 78)
          - R.L. Allen, New York, 1853-1859., 5 items. (Folder 78)
          - John Critcher, Tappahannock, 1835-1837., 7 items. (Folder 78)
          - George P. King, Fredericksburg, 1847-1852., 22 items. (Folder 78)
          - F. Lemoine, Jr., & Co., 1829-1838., 13 items. (Folder 78)
          - Samuel L. Lyell, 1849-1860., 16 items. (Folder 78)
          - Samuel Phillips & Son, Fredericksburg, 1831-1851., 18 items. (Folder 78)
          - Benjamin D. Rust, 1839-1843., 6 items. (Folder 78)
          - George Saunders, 1820-1832., 12 items. (Folder 78)
          - Lyne Shackleford & Co., 1840-1859., 20 items. (Folder 78)
          - Robert B. Sydnor, 1845-1850., 11 items. (Folder 78)
          - William H. Tayloe, 1834-1852., 15 items. (Folder 78)
          - Thomas S. Waugh, 1844-1856., 28 items. (Folder 78)
          - Robert Weir, 1826-1830., 6 items. (Folder 78)
          - Wellford Eastham & Co., 1854-1857., 7 items. (Folder 78)
        - Plantation accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1819-1861., 288 items. (Folder 79)
      - Post office accounts of Robert W. Carter, 1821-1859., 39 items. (Folder 80)
      - Rentals and sales; Receipts and memoranda, 8 items. (Folder 80)
      - Residences, 1823-1861., 75 items. (Folder 80)
        Accounts and correspondence concerning alterations and improvements.
      - Saw mill accounts, 1832-1858., 9 items. (Folder 80)
      - Stable accounts and correspondence of Robert W. Carter, 1821-1859., 97 items. (Folder 81)
        See also Folder 82.
      - Stable accounts and correspondence of Robert W. Carter, concerning the horse, "Senator," 1844-1856., 79 items. (Folder 82)
      - Traveling expenses of Robert W. Carter and family, 1820-1859., 221 items. (Folder 83)
        - Cash Accounts, 1838-1859., 10 items. (Folder 83)
        - Hotel and tavern bills, 1820-1859., 101 items. (Folder 83)
          Arranged into alphabetical order by name of establishment or persons last name.
          - American Hotel, New York, 1848-1850., 3 items. (Folder 83)
          - Astor House, New York, 1848., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Barnum's City Hotel, Baltimore, Maryland, 1843-1855., 10 items. (Folder 83)
          - Belfield (John), 1828., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - City Hotel, Alexandria, D.C., 1842., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - City Hotel, Washington, D.C. (Folder 83)
            See Willard's Hotel.
          - Clarke (Thomas [?]), 1836., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Delavan House, Albany, New York, 1847., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Eagle Hotel, 1822-1843., 3 items. (Folder 83)
          - Exchange Hotel, Richmond, Virginia, 1841-1858., 46 items. (Folder 83)
          - Farmers Hotel, Fredericksburg, Virginia, 1820-1855., 24 items. (Folder 83)
          - Fauquier White Sulphur Springs, Virginia, 1835-1842., 6 items. (Folder 83)
          - Foley ( ), Leesburg, Virginia, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Forbes (Gordon), at Sandy Point, Virginia, 1835-1847., 3 items. (Folder 83)
          - Frederick White Sulphur Springs, Virginia, 1844-1846., 2 items. (Folder 83)
          - Gilmor House, Baltimore, Maryland, 1856., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Goodwin (W.H.), 1841., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Hix (Mrs. Polly), 1851., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Hot Springs, 1847., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Huddleson (J.), Clarksburg, Virginia, 1830., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Hurt [?] (Ann F.), 1823., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Jeffries (Eben), 1842-1848., 3 items. (Folder 83)
          - Jordan (Thomas), Richmond County, Virginia, 1833-1845., 5 items. (Folder 83)
          - Jordan's Springs, 1851-1856., 4 items. (Folder 83)
          - Jones' Hotel, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1841., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Matthews (Thomas), 1837., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Mountain House, Capon Springs, Virginia, 2 items. (Folder 83)
          - Newton (A.G.), 1847-1849., 2 items. (Folder 83)
          - Northern N[eck] Hotel, 1835., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Oldham (Thomas), 1849., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Pavilion Hotel, Berkeley Springs, Virginia, 1843., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Pearson (Elizabeth), 1826., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Pollock's Hotel, 1847., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Powhatan House, Richmond, Virginia, 1839-1841., 9 items. (Folder 83)
          - Richardson (Mrs.), 1832-1836., 16 items. (Folder 83)
          - Singleton (B.), 1820., 2 items. (Folder 83)
          - Smith (A.W.), 1823., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Spotted Tavern., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Stafford Court House Hotel., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Stiff (James M.), 1838., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Taylor's Hotel, Winchester, Virginia, 1847-1851., 5 items. (Folder 83)
          - Temple (John S.), 1828., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Union Hotel, Winchester, Virginia, 1840., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - United States Hotel, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1850., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - United States Hotel, Saratoga Springs, New York, 1848., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Warrenton House, Warrenton, Virginia, 1842., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - Warsaw Hotel, 1833-1834., 2 items. (Folder 83)
          - Washington House, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1848., 2 items. (Folder 83)
          - Webb (Jerry), 1839-1841., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - West Point Hotel, 1848., 1 item. (Folder 83)
          - White Sulphur Springs, Virginia, 1847-1859., 2 items. (Folder 83)
          - Willard's Hotel, Washington, D.C. Formerly the City Hotel, 1844-1852., 19 items. (Folder 83)
          - Winstead (Lucius S.), 1849., 1 item. (Folder 83)
        - Other bills for traveling expenses, 1830-1856., 10 items. (Folder 83)
      - Tuition accounts of Robert W. Carter for the education of his daughters, 1836-1849., 13 items. (Folder 84)
      - Wage accounts and receipts of Robert W. Carter, 1822-1861., 101 items. (Folder 84)
      - Other accounts, bills and receipts of Robert W. Carter, 1819-1861., 78 items. (Folder 84)
        Including 11 items concerning the accounts with the estate of Dominic Bennehan. (1825-1830).
      - Accounts against other persons for goods purchased apparently for Robert W. Carter, 1838-1861., 7 items. (Folder 84)
    - Legal Papers, 1814-1860. (Folder 85-86)
      Arranged into alphabetical order by persons last name.
      - Armstrong, (Thomas); 1814., 1 item. (Folder 85)
        Notice directing Robert W. Carter to attend, at Lancaster Court House, the trial of Thomas Armstrong, captain of artillery attached to the 92nd Regiment, Virginia Militia.
      - Bailey, (Robert); 1845., 1 item. (Folder 85)
        Joseph F. Harvey and David B. Taylor, administrators of Bailey (Robert) et al vs. Robert W. Carter. Suit in Westmoreland County.
      - Berkeley, (Landon C.) and wife to Robert Mayo, Jr., 1848., 1 item. (Folder 85)
        Trust deed covering a tract of land in Westmoreland County, called "Bushfield," to secure a debt due Robert W. Carter.
      - Boggs, (Harmanus) to Robert W. Carter, 1830., 2 items. (Folder 85)
        Deed to a lot of land in the village of Warsaw, 1834, and deed of Edwin Waller and wife conveying the same property to Harmanus Boggs.
      - Buckner, (Elias E.) and wife to Robert W. Carter, 1834., 1 item. (Folder 85)
        Deed to a lot of land in Richmond County near the court house.
      - Carter, (Robert W.)- Agreements and Letters with Overseers, 1815-1860., 53 items. (Folder 85)
        Agreements with overseers, 1815-1854, 24 pieces; and letters from overseers, 1825-1860. 29 items.
      - Carter, (Robert W.)- Land Rental, 1846-1860., 3 items. (Folder 85)
        Agreements for rental of his tract of land in Richmond County, known as "The Distillery."
      - Carter, (Robert W.)- Soldier's claims, 1847-1852., 2 items. (Folder 85)
        Letters concerning soldier's claims of Robert W. Carter.
      - Carter, (Robert W.); 1845-1847., 2 items. (Folder 85)
        E.B. Stephens for Carter (Robert W.) vs. Daniel Atwill.
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. John Bailey's administrators, and a list of suits, 1841-1857., 16 items. (Folder 85)
        Carter (Robert W.) vs. John Bailey's administrators, 1841-1857. 13 items. And, a list of suits brought in Westmoreland County by Robert W. Carter against John Critcher and others to secure debts of John Bailey and of Robert Bailey who was one of the administrators of John Bailey. 1851. 3 items.
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. Bramham's administrator, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. William Y. Dejarnette's executors, 1843-1844., 4 items. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. William Gilmore's executor, Lancaster County, 1828-1831., 2 items. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. Thomas Jones, Jr., 1852., 1 item. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) Agreement with George P. King for purchase of ashes, 1852., 1 item. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) Agreement to purchase from John C. Mitchell his farm in Richmond County, called "Wilna," 1854-1855., 2 items. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. Pursell et al, 1840-1842., 1 item. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. George Saunders, representative of Daniel L. McCarty, 1820., 1 item. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. George Saunders, representative of John Yerby, Jr., 1820., 1 item. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. Thomas S. Waugh, 1853-1857., 1 item. (Folder 85)
      - Carter, (Robert W.) vs. Williamson, 1838-1843., 4 items. (Folder 85)
      - Garner, (Griffin); 1842-1844., 2 items. (Folder 86)
        Agreement regarding sale to Robert W. Carter of one half of the schooner Sally Eleanor, 1842, and an account of Robert W. Carter with Griffin Garner. 1844.
      - Greenlaw, (David) vs. Bennett Knight and Robert W. Carter, 1826-1827., 2 items. (Folder 86)
      - Haynes, ( ); 1849., 1 memo. (Folder 86)
        Deeds of trust to ( ) Conway et al, and to ( ) Pendleton, for ( ) Claybrooke.
      - Hunton, (Thomas H.); 1843., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Agreement with Robert W. Carter regarding the purchase of a tract of land in Westmoreland County, called "Louisville."
      - Ives, (Homer D.); 1842., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Certificate granting to Robert W. Carter the right to use an improved bee-hive patented by William M. Hall of Wallingford, Conn.
      - Lamkin,(J.L.); n.d., 1 memo. (Folder 86)
        Robert W. Carter for Lamkin (J.L.) vs. Thomas S. Waugh et al. Three suits in Charles City County.
      - Landon, (George H.) vs. Robert W. Carter et al, justices for Richmond County, 1854., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Writ to compel them to lay certain levies for a public road and landing.
      - Mason, (Charles); n.d., 1 memo. (Folder 86)
        Agreement with Robert W. Carter concerning the taking of depositions in a certain suit in Spotsylvania County.
      - Merrill, (George) vs. George N. Alderson, 1843., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Suit in Richmond County for amount due him under a trust deed from Jeffries & Oldham to W.Y. Sturman, trustee for Robert W. Carter.
      - Phillips, (Alexander K.) to Robert W. Carter, 1854., 7 items. (Folder 86)
        Trust deed covering his interest in a house and lot in Fredericksburg, and other papers relating thereto.
      - Rains, (Alfred J.) to William H. Tayloe, trustee for Robert W. Carter, 1839-1840., 2 items. (Folder 86)
        Two trust deeds covering slaves.
      - Saunders, ( ) vs. ( ) Palmer, 1836-1844., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Letter from R.E. Scott to Robert W. Carter, who is interested in the suit, giving a financial statement of the case.
      - Smith, (William G.) and wife to William H. Tayloe, trustee for Robert W. Carter, 1839., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Trust deed covering a tract of land in Richmond County.
      - Sydnor, (R.B.); 1852-1853., 2 items. (Folder 86)
        William L. Claybrooke and Thomas Jones, Jr., trustees of Sydnor (R.B.) vs. Elizabeth Edwards et al [including Robert W. Carter]. Suit in Richmond County.
      - Sydnor, (William) and wife to Robert W. Carter, 1823., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Deed to a tract of land in Northumberland and Lancaster Counties.
      - Walker, (Thomas W.) and wife to William Y. Weathers, [trustee for Robert W. Carter]. Trust deed covering a tract of land in Richmond County. 1841., 1 item. (Folder 86)
      - Weathers, (William Y.) to Robert W. Carter, 1844., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Deed to a tract of land in Richmond County.
      - Weathers, (William Y.) to Robert W. Carter, 1848., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Deed of a tract of land in Richmond County, called "The Distillery."
      - Wellford, (Beverley R.) to Armistead N. Wellford [trustee for Robert W. Carter], 1856., 1 item. (Folder 86)
        Trust deed covering a lot in the City of Richmond.
      - Williams, (James) et al vs. Robert W. Carter et al, 1835-1848., 8 items. (Folder 86)
        Suit in Stafford County.
      - Extract from a survey showing line between the property of Lyne Shackleford and that of Robert W. Carter, near Sabine Hall in Richmond County, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 86)
    - Political Papers, 1773-1860, 79 items. (Folder 87-89)
      - Notes and drafts of proposed bills and resolutions in the General Assembly of Virginia, 1801-1858., 17 items. (Folder 87)
      - Notes and drafts of petitions to the Legislature of Virginia, 1773-1858., 4 items. (Folder 87)
      - Letters and statements of a political nature, sent to Robert W. Carter, 1815-1860., 14 items. (Folder 87)
        This group consists chiefly of printed circular letters.
      - Notes and drafts of speeches and of letters for publication, by Robert W. Carter, 1844-1857., 30 items. (Folder 87)
      - Newspaper clippings of a political character, 1815-1846., 14 items. (Folder 87)
      - Letters concerning the selection of Robert W. Carter for various offices, 1825-1858., 29 items. (Folder 88)
      - Polls and data on elections in the counties of Essex, King George, Lancaster, Northumberland, Richmond and Westmoreland, 1827-1857., 14 items. (Folder 88)
      - Certificate appointing Solomon S. Heeth, Robert W. Carter, Benjamin W. Brockenbrough and William D. Garland justices of the peace for the Second District in Richmond County, 1860., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 88)
      - Lists showing certain representatives or officials of Virginia counties, n.d., 2 items. Mutilated. (Folder 88)
      - An address to the people of Virginia, by the members of the General Assembly opposed to the present administration of the Federal Government. Richmond, 1835., 1 item. Printed Pamphlet. (Folder 89)